<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recon on For the curious ones</title>
    <link>https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/tags/recon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recon on For the curious ones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;V 1.2&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:27:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/tags/recon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Subdomain Enumeration:Build yourn own tool</title>
      <link>https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/posts/2021/02/subdomain-enumerationbuild-yourn-own-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:27:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/posts/2021/02/subdomain-enumerationbuild-yourn-own-tool/</guid>
      <description>Hello security enthusiasts welcome to yet another blog. In this blog, we will learn how to create a simple subdomain enumeration tool with python. Subdomain enumeration is a critical step in recon since understanding digital assets play a major role in every pentest activity. For the same, we have a various set of tools and techniques created by awesome people in the hacking community. Sublister, Amass, and the list goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time Eater</title>
      <link>https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-time-eater/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 10:27:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scr1p7k1dd13.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-time-eater/</guid>
      <description>Automating the manual workflow is a great task. This allows us to reduce the time it takes to perform tasks that may take a long time to complete. In penetration testing also we have a wide variety of tools to serve various purposes. For example, let’s consider Recon. If you want to perform recon on targets that have a large scope the initial step will be identifying its digital assets including subdomains, IP’s, etc…But if we don’t have the right tools to do this we will have to use search engine dorks and browse through all the results manually.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
